<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Maxgio&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://maxgio92.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Maxgio&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>http://maxgio92.github.io/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://maxgio92.github.io/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://maxgio92.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A journey into the Linux scheduler</title>
      <link>http://maxgio92.github.io/posts/linux-scheduler-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://maxgio92.github.io/posts/linux-scheduler-journey/</guid>
      <description>Two years ago more or less I started my journey in Linux. I was scared at first and I didn&amp;rsquo;t know where to start from. But then I decided to buy a book - and what a book! - in order to follow a path.
Along the way, I integrated the material with up-to-date documentation from kernel.org and source code. In the meantime, I started to learn C a bit so that I also could have played with what I was learning, step by step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STRIDE threat modeling on Kubernetes pt.6/6: Elevation of privilege</title>
      <link>http://maxgio92.github.io/posts/stride-threat-modeling-kubernetes-elevation-of-privileges/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 14:05:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://maxgio92.github.io/posts/stride-threat-modeling-kubernetes-elevation-of-privileges/</guid>
      <description>Hello everyone, a long time has passed after the 5th part of this journey through STRIDE thread modeling in Kubernetes has been published. If you recall well, STRIDE is a model of threats for identifying security threats, by providing a mnemonic for security threats in six categories:
 Spoofing Tampering Repudiation Information disclosure Denial of service Elevation of privilege  In this last chapter we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about elevation of privilege. Well, this category can be very wide, but let&amp;rsquo;s start thinking about what it can comprises and what we can do against this category of threats.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
